<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>regression | Welcome!</title>
    <link>https://mmel099.github.io/tag/regression/</link>
      <atom:link href="https://mmel099.github.io/tag/regression/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <description>regression</description>
    <generator>Hugo Blox Builder (https://hugoblox.com)</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Wed, 28 Aug 2024 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <image>
      <url>https://mmel099.github.io/media/icon_hubd979b96828314d34ff1ac73d4ae29ee_17978_512x512_fill_lanczos_center_3.png</url>
      <title>regression</title>
      <link>https://mmel099.github.io/tag/regression/</link>
    </image>
    
    <item>
      <title>Used Car Finder: Car Price Decomposition</title>
      <link>https://mmel099.github.io/project/used-car-finder/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 28 Aug 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://mmel099.github.io/project/used-car-finder/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;description&#34;&gt;Description&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The AutoDev API was accessed to gather the data necessary to train the model. Toyota Camrys were used for this project due to their popularity and desirability. Cars produced before 2015 were not included. There were no mileage parameters, meaning new cars were included for this component. Additionally, a radius of 150 miles around Boston was imposed for this search. Most (~85%) Camrys that fit this criteria fell into one of four trims: LE, SE, XLE, XSE. These four were the only ones considered.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the regression model, trim was expanded into dummy (indicator) variables for each trim. Mileage was included as a simple linear effect. Year was incorporated in a complex way: after converting model year into &amp;lsquo;how old&amp;rsquo; each car was, a log transform was applied. The rationale behind this decision came from the logic that a change from &amp;lsquo;year 1&amp;rsquo; to &amp;lsquo;year 2&amp;rsquo; should be more significant than &amp;lsquo;year 6&amp;rsquo; to &amp;lsquo;year 7&amp;rsquo;. Furthermore, each year was granted its own dummy (indicator) variable as well. This added flexibility was introduced to qualify how the data deviates from the assumed log year term. The final model was selected using likelihood ratio tests.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The next step of this project lead me into the area of automation. After generating a script that made a new API call and ran it through the pre-trained regression model. This step produced an estimated price of the car. Comparison of this price with the actual price of the vehicle lead to discount prices. The automation step of this project was a bit tricky but was accomplished with GitHub Actions and YAML. By setting up the YAML file, I enabled a trigger for my script to run every day at midnight and publish the results straight to the github repository.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;data/getCSV.html&#34;&gt;newest&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sweet Dreams: A Regression Analysis of Macronutrient Intake and Sleep Quality</title>
      <link>https://mmel099.github.io/project/sweet-dreams/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 10 Dec 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://mmel099.github.io/project/sweet-dreams/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;abstract&#34;&gt;Abstract&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Sleep quality is a critical component of overall well-being, with numerous factors affecting its duration and depth. Among these factors, nutrition plays a pivotal yet underexplored role in regulating sleep quality. Accurately measuring an individual’s dietary intake is a fundamental challenge in nutritional research. The National Health and Nutrition Examination Survey (NHANES) is an annual survey conducted by the Centers for Disease Control and Prevention (CDC) that collects various health-related data and weights it to be nationally representative.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This project takes advantage of the large sample size of the NHANES dataset to draw associations between macronutrient predictors and sleep quality outcomes. Moreover, the demographic data collected through NHANES others us a way to investigate relevant confounders that are associated with both nutrition and sleep. We identified three final outcome variables related to sleep quality. One outcome was the duration of sleep, rounded to the closest half-hour, on weekdays; this outcome was modeled using multiple linear regression. Another relevant outcome was an indicator for whether the participant had ever told a doctor about trouble sleeping; this was modeled using multinomial regression. The final outcome was a categorical variable asking how often a participant felt overly sleepy during the past month. Furthermore, we aggregated our three sleep outcomes into a single overall metric of sleep quality and fit a Quasi-Poisson regression model.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Fiber intake was found to be positively associated with sleep quality, across linear, multinomial, and Quasi-Poisson regressions. Protein was found to have a negative association with length and quality of sleep across the Quasi-Poisson and linear models. Carbohydrates were found to have a harmful effect on sleep quality in the adjusted multinomial models.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Hello R Markdown</title>
      <link>https://mmel099.github.io/post/2020-12-01-r-rmarkdown/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Dec 2020 21:13:14 -0500</pubDate>
      <guid>https://mmel099.github.io/post/2020-12-01-r-rmarkdown/</guid>
      <description>


&lt;div id=&#34;r-markdown&#34; class=&#34;section level1&#34;&gt;
&lt;h1&gt;R Markdown&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is an R Markdown document. Markdown is a simple formatting syntax for authoring HTML, PDF, and MS Word documents. For more details on using R Markdown see &lt;a href=&#34;http://rmarkdown.rstudio.com&#34; class=&#34;uri&#34;&gt;http://rmarkdown.rstudio.com&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You can embed an R code chunk like this:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre class=&#34;r&#34;&gt;&lt;code&gt;summary(cars)
##      speed           dist       
##  Min.   : 4.0   Min.   :  2.00  
##  1st Qu.:12.0   1st Qu.: 26.00  
##  Median :15.0   Median : 36.00  
##  Mean   :15.4   Mean   : 42.98  
##  3rd Qu.:19.0   3rd Qu.: 56.00  
##  Max.   :25.0   Max.   :120.00
fit &amp;lt;- lm(dist ~ speed, data = cars)
fit
## 
## Call:
## lm(formula = dist ~ speed, data = cars)
## 
## Coefficients:
## (Intercept)        speed  
##     -17.579        3.932&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div id=&#34;including-plots&#34; class=&#34;section level1&#34;&gt;
&lt;h1&gt;Including Plots&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You can also embed plots. See Figure &lt;a href=&#34;#fig:pie&#34;&gt;1&lt;/a&gt; for example:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre class=&#34;r&#34;&gt;&lt;code&gt;par(mar = c(0, 1, 0, 1))
pie(
  c(280, 60, 20),
  c(&amp;#39;Sky&amp;#39;, &amp;#39;Sunny side of pyramid&amp;#39;, &amp;#39;Shady side of pyramid&amp;#39;),
  col = c(&amp;#39;#0292D8&amp;#39;, &amp;#39;#F7EA39&amp;#39;, &amp;#39;#C4B632&amp;#39;),
  init.angle = -50, border = NA
)&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;figure&#34;&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;display:block;&#34; id=&#34;fig:pie&#34;&gt;&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;img src=&#34;https://mmel099.github.io/post/2020-12-01-r-rmarkdown/index.en_files/figure-html/pie-1.png&#34; alt=&#34;A fancy pie chart.&#34; width=&#34;672&#34; /&gt;
&lt;p class=&#34;caption&#34;&gt;
Figure 1: A fancy pie chart.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
